Guide to the Laura Foreman Papers 1949-2001 MSS.122
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series VI: Video recordings, 1973-1985; 41.25 Linear Feet 33 Paige Cartons
  - Subseries A: Original tapes
    - 1. #164 Dub 2. #165 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0381 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0381)
    - 1. #165 Dub, cont 2. #166 Dub 3. #167 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0382 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0382)
    - 168 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0383 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0383)
    - #169 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0384 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0384)
    - 1. #170 Dub 2. #171 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0385 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0385)
    - #172 a deux Edit Dub, 1974; ID: 122.0386 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0386)
    - 1. #173 a deux Dub II 2. #174 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0387 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0387)
    - #175 Heirlooms Dubs, 1977; ID: 122.0388 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0388)
    - #176 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0389 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0389)
    - #177 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0390 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0390)
    - #178 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0391 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0391)
    - 1. #179 Dub 2. #180 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0392 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0392)
    - 1. #188 Dub, cont 2. #181 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0393 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0393)
    - #182 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0394 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0394)
    - 1. #181 Dub, cont 2. #183 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0395 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0395)
    - 1. #182 Dub, cont 2. #184 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0396 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0396)
    - #185 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0397 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0397)
    - 1. #186 Dub 2. #191 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0398 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0398)
    - Heirlooms III - Dup, 1977; ID: 122.0399 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0399)
    - Heirlooms Section I - Dup, 1977; ID: 122.0400 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0400)
    - #198 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0401 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0401)
    - #199 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0402 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0402)
    - #200 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0403 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0403)
    - 1. #201 Dub 2. #202 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0404 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0404)
    - 1. #202 Dub, cont 2. #203 Dub 3. #204 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0405 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0405)
    - 1. #204 Dub, cont 2. #205 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0406 (Box 147, Media ID: 122.0406)
    - #206 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0407 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0407)
    - 1. #207 Dub, cont 2. #208 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0408 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0408)
    - 1. #208 Dub, cont 2. #209 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0409 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0409)
    - 1. #209 Dub, cont 2. #210 Dub 3. #211 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0410 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0410)
    - 1. #211 Dub, cont 2. #212 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0411 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0411)
    - 1. #212 Dub, cont 2. #213 Dub 3. #215 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0412 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0412)
    - #214 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0413 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0413)
    - 1. #216 City Dub 2. #217 City Dub, 1975; ID: 122.0414 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0414)
    - 1. #217 Dub, cont 2. #218 Dub 3. #219 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0415 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0415)
    - 1. #219 Dub, cont 2. #220 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0416 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0416)
    - 1. #221 Dub Part I 2. #222 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0417 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0417)
    - 1. #222 Dub, cont 2. #225 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0418 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0418)
    - 1. #226 Dub, cont 2. #227 Dub 3. 122.0228 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0419 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0419)
    - 1. #229 Dub 2. #230 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0420 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0420)
    - 1. #230 Dub, cont 2. #232 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0421 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0421)
    - 1. #232 Dub, cont 2. #233 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0422 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0422)
    - 1. #234 Dub 2. #235 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0423 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0423)
    - 1. 236 Dub 2.173 Part I Dub, undated; ID: 122.0424 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0424)
    - 1. #235 Dub, cont 2. #221 Dub Part II 3.- #236 Dub, undated; ID: 122.0425 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0425)
    - Untitled NYSCA Work Tape #2, 1978; ID: 122.0426 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0426)
    - Art/Video/Sound - Tape I, 1979; ID: 122.0427 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0427)
    - Focal Ingenuity, 1988; ID: 122.0428 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0428)
      Duration: 8 minutes
    - Shacks of America, 1988; ID: 122.0429 (Box 148, Media ID: 122.0429)
      Duration: 7 minutes
    - Unknown #1, undated; ID: 122.0430 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0430)
    - Unknown #2, undated; ID: 122.0431 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0431)
    - Unknown #3, undated; ID: 122.0432 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0432)
    - Unknown #4, undated; ID: 122.0433 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0433)
    - Unknown #5, undated; ID: 122.0434 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0434)
    - Unknown #6, undated; ID: 122.0435 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0435)
    - Unknown Sony 30 #1, undated; ID: 122.0436 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0436)
    - Artichoke For Two, undated; ID: 122.0437 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0437)
    - Fresh - Reg Dens., undated; ID: 122.0438 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0438)
    - Unknown / Blank, undated; ID: 122.0439 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0439)
    - Sony Virgin Tape #1, 1980; ID: 122.0440 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0440)
    - Sony Virgin Tape #2, 1980; ID: 122.0441 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0441)
    - Unknown 3M Tape, undated; ID: 122.0442 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0442)
    - Unknown Sony 30 #2, undated; ID: 122.0443 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0443)
    - Unknown Sony 30 #3, undated; ID: 122.0444 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0444)
    - Unknown Scotch Scratch Tape, undated; ID: 122.0445 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0445)
    - Unknown Sony 60 #1, undated; ID: 122.0446 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0446)
    - Unknown Sony 60 #2, undated; ID: 122.0447 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0447)
    - Unknown Sony Scratch Tape #1, 1978; ID: 122.0448 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0448)
    - Unknown Sony Scratch Tape #2, undated; ID: 122.0449 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0449)
    - Unknown Sony Scratch Tape #3, undated; ID: 122.0450 (Box 149, Media ID: 122.0450)
    - AFI Master With Uncorrected Audio, undated; ID: 122.0451 (Box 150, Media ID: 122.0451)
    - Reel II 1st Half, undated; ID: 122.0452 (Box 150, Media ID: 122.0452)
    - AFI - Test Dub, 1978; ID: 122.0453 (Box 150, Media ID: 122.0453)
    - First Part of AFI Master, undated; ID: 122.0454 (Box 150, Media ID: 122.0454)
    - Unknown Sony 60 #3, undated; ID: 122.0455 (Box 150, Media ID: 122.0455)
    - Unknown Sony 60 #4, undated; ID: 122.0456 (Box 150, Media ID: 122.0456)
    - Unknown Sony 60 #5, undated; ID: 122.0457 (Box 150, Media ID: 122.0457)
    - Unknown Sony 60 #6, undated; ID: 122.0458 (Box 150, Media ID: 122.0458)
  - Subseries B: Preservation Masters - CLOSED
    CLOSED
    - ID: 122.0461 - 122.0479 (Box PM 27)
- Series VII: Films
  Series VII contains a small amount of moving image documentations captured on film instead of video.
  Films have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - Subseries A: Original films
    - New G & S Super 8, undated; ID: 122.0459 (Box 150, Media ID: 122.0459)
      Gauge: Super8mm
    - How to Organize a Film Workshop, 1978; ID: 122.0460 (Box 150, Media ID: 122.0460)
      Gauge: 16mm
- Series VIII: Sound recordings
  Series VIII contains audio recordings, and is currently awaiting processing. For more information on this series, contact a Fales Archivist.
  Sound recordings have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
- Series IX: Objects, 1.25 Linear Feet 1 Paige Carton
  Series IX contains various items once owned by Foreman or employed in her artworks, including props from dance performances.
  The objects in Series IX are arranged thematically, if rather loosely. Every object has its own identification number. The first objects listed are those that pertain to Foreman's dance career. Those that were difficult to align with any part of Foreman's career follow.
  - Photographic Print - unidentified event, mounted on foam core and 11x14 card, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0001)
  - Silver whistle, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0002)
  - Silver whistle, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0003)
  - Silver whistle, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0004)
  - Silver whistle, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0005)
  - Silver whistle, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0006)
  - Silver whistle with chain, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0007)
  - Black whistle, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0008)
  - Black whistle, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0009)
  - Small speaker / microphone, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0010)
  - Small speaker / microphone, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0011)
  - Choreographers Theatre button; reads "Modern Dance Power", undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0012)
  - Costume worn by Satoru Shimazaki in Entries, 1978 (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0013)
  - Large copper bell on a long, multi-colored beaded necklace, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0014)
  - Six copper bells and multi-colored beads tied on a leather string, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0015)
  - Five small copper bells tied on an orange rope; label attached reads "Camel Bells", undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0016)
  - Five small gold bells tied on an orange rope, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0017)
  - Two small gold bells tied on an orange rope, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0018)
  - Copper cowbell, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0019)
  - Gold bell, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0020)
  - Small silver bell, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0021)
  - Button-shaped silver bell, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0022)
  - Thin orange, green and white rope tied in a bow, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0023)
  - Small tambourine, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0024)
  - Ziploc bag containing four keys; marked "Play Keys", undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0025)
  - Plastic zipper case containing CCT Corporate Seal Embosser, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0026)
  - Composers and Choreographers Theatre Corporate Seal Embosser, 1966 (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0027)
  - Medal in case, from International Film and TV Festival of New York, 1981 (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0028)
  - "Dancing Finger Bear" toy, in original packaging, 1981 (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0029)
  - "Bag Full of Laughs" Toy, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0030)
    D batteries removed in the for preservation purposes
  - "Bag Full of Laughs" toy, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0031)
  - "Baby Piano" toy, in original packaging, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0032)
  - Six intertwined red and white pipe cleaners, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0033)
  - Small jewel box, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0034)
  - Small knitted kite made of yarn and two popsicle sticks, undated (Box 151, Object ID: 122.2.0035)
- Oversize Series I: Files
  - Apartment Floor Plans, undated (Box 155, Folder 1)
  - Apartment Floor Plans, undated (Folder 6)
  - Birthday Card for Laura Foreman, 1974 (Folder 4 Right)
  - Choreoconcerts Flyer Draft, 1974 (Box 153, Folder 1)
  - Choreographers' Theatre Flyer Drafts, undated (Box 153, Folder 2)
  - Composers' and Choreographers' Theatre Disbursement Ledgers, 1973-1975 (Box 153, Folder 3-4)
  - High School Class photographs with student signatures, 1952, 1955 (Folder 3 Right)
  - Photocopied Drawings, undated (Box 153, Folder 5)
  - Photocopy - Brooklyn Journal, 1978 (Box 153, Folder 6)
    includes poems and writing by Foreman's friend, Palmer Hasty
  - Press, 1990 (Box 152, Folder 1)
  - Schematic Drawings, undated (Box 153, Folder 7)
  - Schematic Drawings, undated (Box 155, Folder 2)
  - Souyun Yi Gallery Design Charts, c1998 (Box 153, Folder 8)
- Oversize Series IV: Photographic Material
  - "Coney Island Cray-Pas", 1981 (Box 152, Folder 2)
    Contact Sheets
  - "Coney Island Cray-Pas", 1981 (Box 153, Folder 9)
  - "Wallwork" in Paris and Stockholm (by John Watts), 1981 (Box 152, Folder 3-4)
  - Portraits, undated (Box 152, Folder 5)
  - Portraits, undated (Box 153, Folder 10)
  - Portraits, undated (Box 155, Folder 3-5)
  - Personal, undated (Box 152, Folder 6)
  - Portraits and performance photos of John Watts, 1977 (Box 153, Folder 11)
  - Photos of unidentified persons and events, undated (Box 152, Folder 7)
  - Photos of unidentified persons and events, undated (Box 153, Folder 12)
- Oversize Series V: Artworks, Sketches and Posters
  - "Birdhouse as Metaphor" Sketches, 1986, undated (Box 153, Folder 13-17)
  - Chambers Street Artists Exhibition Poster, 1981 (Box 155, Folder 7)
  - Costume Design Sketches, undated (Box 153, Folder 18-19)
  - Fiber R/evolution Exhibition Poster, Milwaukee Art Museum, 1986 (Folder 2 Left)
  - "Gum Art" Sketch, undated (Box 152, Folder 8)
  - "Heirlooms" Posters, 1977 (Box 155, Folder 8)
  - "Luncheonette Art Work" Sketch, 1984 (Box 155, Folder 9)
  - Mixed Media Paintings, undated (Box 153, Folder 20-22)
  - "Not For Sale" Exhibition Poster, undated (Box 152, Folder 9)
  - Paintings from "Vermont Colony School", 1988 (Box 153, Folder 23-28)
  - Shacks of America Photocollages, undated (Box 152, Folder 10)
  - Shacks of America Photocollages, undated (Folder 7)
  - Sketchbooks, undated (Box 152, Folder 11-12)
  - Sketchbooks, undated (Box 155, Folder 10-11)
  - Spare Parts Exhibition Poster, 1983 (Box 155, Folder 12)
  - "Wallwork" Poster, 1981 (Box 155, Folder 13)
  - "Word Painting" / "I have nothing to paint and I'm painting it", 1983 (Box 152, Folder 13)
  - Untitled Artworks, undated (Box 154, Folder 1-2)
  - Untitled Sketches, undated (Box 152, Folder 14-16)
  - Untitled Sketches, undated (Box 155, Folder 14-18)
  - Untitled Sketches, undated (Box 154, Folder 3-37)
  - Untitled Sketches, undated (Folder 1 Left, Folder 5)